# **JOSE MARTOS**

#### FRONT-END DEVELOPER & DESIGN ADVOCATE

## **TECH STACK**

HTML5, CSS3, SASS, CSS-in-JS ES6+, React, Vue.js, jQuery, TypeScript, Jest, Node.js, Express

Next.js, Webpack, Parcel, Gulp, Babel, ESlint, Prettier, PostCSS

RWD, Page optimisation, SEO JIRA, Git(flow), GitLab, Docker

# **COURSES**

- React 16.8 (10h | 2019)
- Javascript testing practises and principles (5h | 2019)
- API design in Node.js (4h | 2019)
- Web performance (5h | 2019)
- Typescript 3 (5h | 2019)
- Photoshop CS5 (80h | 2012)
- Systems & Networks (534h | 2006)

# **TOOLS**

- VS Code, WebStorm, Sublime Text
- Figma, Invision, Zeplin, Avocode, Photoshop
- Sequel Pro, HeidiSQL, Compass

# **LANGUAGES**

Spanish: Native

English: C1 | German: B1

# PERSONAL INTERESTS

Trekking, Traveling, Reading, Photography, Martial arts

# CONTACT

martosjosele@gmail.com Based in Munich 10.07.1987 – Málaga, Spain github.com/josemartos

#### PERSONAL SUMMARY

Developer with a focus on **efficiency** and minimalism. I am eager for new experiences, a creative problem solver, and fast **learner**. When working, I value code **quality**, sense of humour, **team-work**, reliability, and proactivity. I am happy to live in a time with great tools and frameworks to assist developers in building applications better and faster.

# **PROFESSIONAL CAREER**

# Front-end Developer & Junior UI Designer

Flyla GmbH - Munich (Nov 2019 - today)

- Refactored the front-end code to diminish the current technical debt looking for consistency. Worked with *React* and *Typescript*
- Improved the look and feel of the site with a minimal approach using Figma
- Won the 1st prize in the IATA AIR Hackathon of Seattle 2020 "Best booking experience for non-corporate"

# **Front-end Developer**

Pantaflix GmbH - Berlin (Mar 2017 - Sep 2018)

- Implemented a web app tool for the customer care department using *Vue.js*, responsible for the set-up with *Webpack* and further development
- Responsible for the front-end on a CMS for filmmakers and consumers, using plain *JavaScript* and Twig. Microservice architecture oriented
- Implemented new features on the main website, using jQuery and Node.js

# **Front-end Developer**

Team2Venture GmbH - Berlin (Oct 2014 - Feb 2017)

- Participated in a white-label CMS for external companies to handle freelancers and projects, using plain <code>JavaScript</code> and <code>Scala</code> templates
- Implemented new features on the main website using  $\it Backbone$  , participating on a migration from RequireJS to  $\it Browserify + Gulp$

# **Full-stack Developer**

Dreamsite - Madrid (Jun 2012 - Sep 2014)

- Developed +10 corporation websites using *jQuery* and PHP
- Integrated designs in Wordpress pages

# Junior Full-stack Developer & UI Designer

Uniagro SL - Málaga (Jul 2009 - May 2012)

- Designed and developed +15 corporation websites using *jQuery* and PHP
- Designed logos and banners

#### **EDUCATION**

Senior Technician in Computer Applications Development (2007 - 2009) IES Pedro Espinosa, Antequera, Málaga